好了  时间就要到了
Okay, it's almost time.
好了  我们回顾一下吧
All right. Shall we review?
请吧
Please.
好了  据卡莱布说
All right, according to Caleb,
手机会在8点准时响起
this phone is gonna ring at exactly 8:00 a.m.
由于有卫星定位设置
Now, because it's GPS-enabled,
只能在这个公园接通
it will only work in this particular park.
到时  一个经过电子变声的声音
At which time, an electronically altered voice --
很可能属于洛克塞特  就会给卡莱布下达命令
most likely LokSat's -- will issue Caleb his orders.
我会拦截他的命令  并用来电中继进行追踪
Orders that I'll intercept and trace with a cellular relay.
好  我给你接入中继
Okay, I'm gonna attach you to the relay.
你连好了吗  维克拉姆
You connected, Vikram?
已经同步  可以开始了
Synched up and ready to go.
各位  终于到了
Guys, this is it.
如果一切顺利  我们就能查明洛克塞特的身份
If all goes well, we'll identify LokSat
终于扳倒他
and finally take his ass down.
如果出了岔子
And if anything goes sideways,
我们立刻终止行动
we immediately shut it down
去分局见面  知道了吗
and meet up at the precinct, got it?
收到
Roger that.
你跟我想到一起了吗
You thinking what I'm thinking?
你也想吃巧克力软糖冰棒吗
You want a Fudgsicle, too?
我知道  可能是陷阱
I know. Could be a trap.
卡莱布虽然投诚了  并不代表
Just because Caleb switched sides doesn't mean
洛克塞特没有一直在监视他
that LokSat doesn't have him under surveillance.
这些人都可能是洛克塞特的手下
Any one of these people could be a LokSat agent
甚至是洛克塞特本人
or even LokSat himself.
你想赌一把吗
Do you care to put a wager on it?
赌什么
Wager on what?
赌哪个是洛克塞特
On which one's LokSat.
我赌20块是那个咸猪手瑜伽教练
I got 20 bucks says it's that handsy yogi over there.
我赌是红发斑点妹
I'm going for the Carrot Top Cruella De Vil.
等等  她是不是有点像你第一个前妻啊
Wait, wait -- Does she look a bit like your first ex-wife?
是有点
She kind of does.
天啊  我的前妻会是洛克塞特吗
Oh, my God. Could my ex-wife be LokSat?
因为在很多方面  那能解释通很多事了
'Cause in a lot of ways, that would make perfect sense.
好了  维克拉姆  开始了
All right, Vikram. Here we go.
早  卡莱布
Good morning, Caleb.
我有急事要你处理
I have an urgent matter for you.
布鲁克林百老汇和弗莱辛
There's an abandoned warehouse
交界口有个废弃仓库
near Broadway and Flushing in Brooklyn.
停车场有一个保安站
There's a security booth in the parking lot.
今天中午将新银行路由号码
Dead-drop a flash drive with the new bank routing numbers
放在保安站的最上面抽屉里
in the top drawer of that booth at precisely noon today
我的会计会去取回
for my accountant to retrieve.
暂时就这样
That is all for now.
追踪到了吗
Did you get a trace?
不知道  来电太短
I don't know. The call was short.
等等  有发现
Wait. I got something.
糟糕  显示来电地点是DYE2
Oh, no. It says here the call originated in DYE-2.
那是什么
A-- What's that?
位于北极的废弃的冷战时期雷达站
It's an abandoned Cold War radar station in the Arctic Circle.
洛克塞特肯定在那儿建立了来电中继
LokSat must've set up a cellular relay there.
各位  这是条死路
Guys, this is a dead end.
或许是机会
Or is it an opportunity?
我们都听到了卡莱布的指示
We all heard Caleb's instructions.
洛克塞特的会计会在传递点暴露身份
LokSat's accountant is going to expose himself at that dead drop.
这才叫食物链上端
Talk about high on the food chain.
如果我们抓到洛克塞特的会计
We get LokSat's accountant...
我们就能更靠近洛克塞特
It could bring us one step closer to LokSat himself.
维克拉姆  给卡莱布发一封加密邮件
Vikram, send an encrypted e-mail to Caleb.
他得去传递点
He's gonna have to show up at that dead drop.
你去找海莉
And you have to get ahold of Hayley.
我们需要一切帮手
We need all the help we can get.
不管这工作我做了多久
No matter how long I've been on the job,
烧死的总让我受不了
the burned ones always get me.
蕾妮  查到身份了吗
Yo, Lanie, we have a name?
没有  无名氏
No, he's a John Doe.
知道车是谁的吗
Do we know who owns the car?
昨晚在二手车停车场偷来的
It was stolen last night from a used car lot.
很遗憾  我此刻没法提供更多情况
Unfortunately, I can't tell you much right now
只知道死者是男性
other than the victim was male.
而且  看他腿  手和脸
And you see these burnt remnants
周围的灼烧残留物
around his legs, hands, and face?
-胶带吗  -对
- Duct tape? - Yep.
被害人被绑住  堵了嘴
Our victim was bound, gagged,
而且凶手点火的时候他还活着
and very much alive when the killer lit the fire.
死得好惨
Hell of a way to go.
这是安德科特的箱子  高档货
Yo, this is an Andercott briefcase -- very high-end.
边框上的序列号还能看得到
Can still make out the serial number on the frame.
如果走运  被害人注册过
If we're lucky, our victim registered it,
我们就能查到名字了
and we can get his name that way.
凶手选择这里是有原因的
Killer chose this location for a reason --
两边都是闲置建筑
vacant buildings on either side,
周围没有监控
not a security camera in sight.
昨晚又下过雨  所以
It rained last night, so, clearly,
这些印痕是雨后才留下的
these tracks were made afterwards.
-可能是凶手走向逃跑车时留下的  -嗯
- Might be from the killer walking to his getaway car. - Yeah.
给鞋印和车辙都
You know, why don't we make impressions
做个石膏模吧
of all the shoeprints and tire tracks?
说不定能走运
Maybe we'll get lucky.
我需要这个做什么
And what do I need these for?
我说了  你是盯梢的
Like I said, you're the lookout.
我们监视洛克塞特的会计时
W-When we do our surveillance of LokSat's accountant,
你得去找个制高点
we're gonna need you to find a high vantage point,
做我们的天眼
be our eye in the sky.
那里面没有吉他  是吧
There's not a guitar in there, is there?
不是能奏乐的那种
Not the kind that plays music.
海莉
Uh, Hayley.
万一出事了
I-In case anything goes wrong...
我会把玛莎和阿丽克西斯带来这里  保护他们
I will get Martha and Alexis here, and I will protect them.
我保证
You have my word.
谢谢你  我欠你个人情
Thank you. I owe you one.
应该是欠了十几个了
And by one, I mean more like one dozen.
等我们扳倒了洛克塞特
After we take down LokSat,
我打算递交辞呈了
I am thinking I might tender my resignation.
你想回去做政府分析员吗
So, you want to go back to being a government analyst?
我想回到无聊的人生中
I want to go back to being boring.
我都忘记那滋味了
Kind of forgotten what that feels like.
我知道听上去大概挺蠢的
I know that probably sounds stupid.
不  完全不会
No. No, not at all.
谢谢你跟我一起追查
Thank you for doing this with me.
开玩笑吗  该谢谢你才对
Are you kidding? Thank you for...everything.
就要到头了
Almost there.
是啊  就到头了
Yeah, almost.
说起来  我们该走了
Speaking of, we should head out.
警监
Captain.
对不起  我们打扰什么了吗
I'm sorry, are we -- are we interrupting something?
没有
Uh, no.
怎么了
What's going on?
我们的凶案有线索了
Well, we got a lead on our homicide.
凶手逃跑车的车辙
The tire impressions made by our killer's getaway car
表明轮胎是交错的
show that the wheels were staggered,
就是说前轮
meaning the ones in the back
比后轮小
were larger than the ones up front.
那么是外国车
So, the car's exotic.
准确说  这表明车是中置或后置引擎的
Specifically, it means that the car was either mid- or rear-engine.
虽然没有犯罪现场附近的
So, even though we don't have any traffic cams
监控录像  我们也能翻查
from near the crime scene, we can scrub footage
周边地带的监控录像
from the surrounding areas and then --
希望能找到符合特点的车
Hopefully find a car that fits the bill.
好  干得好  你们继续吧
Okay. Good job. I'll leave you guys to it.
贝克特
Yo, Beckett.
有什么事需要我们知道的吗
Is there something going on that we should know about?
没有
No.
维克拉姆  能看到保安站了吗
Vikram, you got a view on that security booth?
毫无遮挡
Completely unobstructed.
好吧  我们俩合力
Okay, between the both of us,
应该能清晰拍到会计了
we should get a good photo of that accountant.
你确定这就足够了吗
Are you sure that's all we'll need?
是啊  维克拉姆会用面部识别
Yeah, Vikram's gonna run the accountant's photo
分辨会计的照片
through facial recognition.
我们查明身份后再找到他
We'll I.D. it, and then we'll track him down later.
海莉  就位了吗
Hayley, you in position?
是的
That's an affirmative.
你的吉他调好音  可以演奏了吗
Your guitar all tuned up, ready to play?
刚好
Just about.
卡塞尔  你看到什么了吗
Castle, you see anything?
没有  就两只下水道老鼠在争一块披萨饼
No. Just two sewer rats fighting over a piece of pizza.
-海莉  -什么事
- Hayley? - Yeah?
看到什么了吗
You see anything?
西线无战事
All quiet on the Western front.
我不懂
I don't get it.
卡莱布给我回了加密邮件
Caleb sent me back an encrypted e-mail
说他会在中午准时来传递点
confirming he'd make the drop at noon sharp.
别担心  他会来的
Don't worry. He'll be here.
你用多少的光圈值
What f-stop are you using?
什么
Excuse me?
光圈值  是相机的一个功能
F-stop, it's a function on the camera.
就是曝光度...
It tells it how much light to permit --
我知道那什么意思
Yeah, no, I know what an f-stop is.
我们又不是在给《国家地理》拍照片
This isn't a shoot for National Geographic.
我设的自动
It's on auto.
自动
Auto.
不不不  绝不能用自动
No, no, no. Never use auto.
来  我给你调
Here, let me get that for you.
卡塞尔  别动我的东西
Castle, stop messing with my stuff.
你不是喜欢我动你的"东西"吗
I thought you liked it when I messed with your stuff?
真不想打断你们的情话
Hey, um, I hate to interrupt your pillow talk,
但卡莱布·布朗到了
but Caleb Brown's just arrived.
好了  各位  招子放亮
All right, guys. Eyes peeled.
会计肯定就在附近
The accountant's gonna be nearby.
卡莱布去放东西了
Okay, Caleb's making the drop.
埃斯波  我有点忙
Espo, I'm kind of busy here.
我知道  听着  我追踪了
I know, I know, but listen -- I traced the serial number
犯罪现场那个箱子的序列号
on that briefcase from the crime scene.
箱子是卡莱布·布朗的
It belongs to Caleb Brown.
所以我让实验室检测了DNA  是匹配的
So, I had the lab run his DNA. It's a match.
卡莱布死了  他是死者
Caleb's dead. Here's our victim.
埃斯波  你在吗
Espo? Are you there?
怎么了
What is it?
那不是卡莱布
That's not Caleb.
卡塞尔  这是陷阱
Castle, this is a trap.
有人在吗  有人听得到吗
Anyone there? Can you hear us?
海莉  维克拉姆
Hayley? Vikram?
他们有干扰器  卡塞尔  我们被切断了联系
They got a frequency jammer, Castle. We're cut off.
开火
Open fire!
卡塞尔
Castle!
狙击手
Sniper!
我无法击中
I don't have a clear shot.
我没子弹了
I'm out.
我也是
Yeah, same.
上车
Get in!
梅森
Mason?
我们走
We're out of here.
没人跟踪  我们安全了
No one's following. We're clear.
简直太酷了
That was amazing!
梅森  你真是个救命恩人
Mason, you, sir, are quite literally a lifesaver.
这逃跑车也够牛逼
And talk about a getaway vehicle.
韩国烤肉玉米卷车  开什么玩笑
A Korean barbecue taco truck? Are you serious?
有人现在饿了吗
Is anyone hungry right now?
我绝对能做个泡菜炸玉米粉圆饼
Because I could totally whip up some kimchi tostadas.
-你是谁  -别激动
- Who are you? - Easy now.
别别别
No, no, no, no.
凯特  凯特  这位是梅森·伍德
Kate, Kate, Kate. This is Mason Wood.
他是最强侦探协会的主席
He's the head of the Greatest Detective Society.
我跟你说过在洛杉矶结识了他
I told you about meeting him in L.A.
那不代表他值得信任
That doesn't mean that we can trust him.
好吧  别信任我  但你能不能
Fine, don't trust me, but would you mind
别拿那玩意指着我
pointing that thing away from me?
让我有点紧张
It makes me just a bit nervous.
别担心  她没子弹了
Don't worry. She's out of bullets.
你为什么要告诉他
Why would you tell him that?
因为他救了我们  他是朋友
Because he saved our lives, and he's a friend!
他刚巧开着韩国烤肉玉米饼车
Who just happened to be at the right place
在我们急需的时候冲到了我们所在的地点
at the right time with the right Korean barbecue taco truck?
我还是很怀疑
I don't think so.
她说的有点道理
She does make a good point.
梅森  你为什么会来
Mason, what are you doing here?
你妈妈叫我来的
Your mother sent me.
我妈妈
My mother?!
你认识玛莎
You know Martha?
不是那个妈妈  另一个妈妈
No, not that mother -- the other one.
你的继母  丽塔
The, uh, stepmother, Rita.
你怎么认识她的
How do you know her?
很久以前  我曾是国务院的律师
Once upon a time I was a lawyer with the State Department,
一次执行海外任务时
and, on an overseas assignment,
丽塔搭乘我的车队去大使馆
Rita was in my convoy going to the embassy.
我们遭受了攻击  被绑为人质
We were hit. We were taken hostage.
要不是丽塔  我...
If it hadn't been for Rita, I...
我欠她个人情  好吗
Look, I just owe her, all right?
她打电话说你俩
And when she called and said that you two
插手了危险的事
were sticking your noses into something dangerous
需要有人照顾  我就同意了
and needed a babysitter, I said okay.
她有跟你说洛克塞特  以及...
Did she tell you about LokSat, how it's connected --
行了  打住
Okay, just stop right there.
不管这是怎么回事
Now, whatever this is
不管你们明显是激怒了谁
and whoever you have obviously pissed off,
我知道的越少
the less I know about this,
我活下去的几率就越大
the better my chances are of staying alive.
记住  我只是个保姆
Remember, I'm just a babysitter,
我可以给你们换尿布  喂奶
so I'll change your diapers and feed you your bottle and...
从雇佣军突击队手中救出你们
save you from a strike force of armed mercenaries,
但我不会加入你们的战斗
but I am not joining your fight.
手机给我
Here, give me your cellphone.
杀手小队能追查到我们  我把手机丢掉去
Hit squad could find us on it. I'm gonna dump them.
给
Here.
你们随意拿
You're welcome to take anything you need.
都是不可追踪的
It's all untraceable.
祝你俩好运
Good luck to both of you.
我们怎么报答你
How do we thank you?
你在洛杉矶解决了我朋友的谋杀案
You solved my friend's murder back in L.A.
这就算扯平了
Let's call it even.
给
Here.
那是怎么搞的
How did that happen?
我们很小心了
We were careful.
洛克塞特肯定是发现卡莱布背叛了他
LokSat must've discovered that Caleb betrayed him
得知了我们的消息
and then got wind of us.
洛克塞特杀了卡莱布  然后他只需要
So LokSat killed Caleb, and then all he had to do
黑入卡莱布的账户
was hack in to Caleb's account
给维克拉姆发邮件
and send a fake e-mail to Vikram
假意同意去进行传递
agreeing to make that drop.
洛克塞特会继续来追杀我们的
LokSat is going to keep coming for us.
或者更糟  他会追杀我们的家人
Or worse, he's gonna come after our families.
好吧  我爸爸外出办事了
Okay, well, my dad's away on business,
他暂时没事
so he's okay for now,
但你得让海莉去接阿丽克西斯和玛莎
but you got to get Hayley to pick up Alexis and Martha
带他们去侦探社的安全屋
and take them to the P.I. Office safe room.
维克拉姆呢  他也有危险
What about Vikram? He's in danger, too.
我会找到他
I'll track him down.
然后我们碰面  再做计划
Then we'll meet up, and we'll make a plan.
不不  别那副表情
No, no, no. Come on. Don't give me that face.
说  "我们回头侦探社见"
Just say, "We'll meet at the P.I. Office."
我们回头侦探社见
We'll meet at the P.I. Office.
好
Okay.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
后置中置引擎车还是没找到
Still haven't found any rear or mid-engine cars yet,
但我还要翻查好几个摄像头
but I still have several traffic cams to scrub through so...
看这个
Check this out.
鉴证组在烧毁车里找到了一则信息
CSU uncovered a message in that burned-out trunk.
我觉得是卡莱布留下的
Now, I think it was from Caleb.
肯定是凶手开车到无人停车场的路上
He must've scratched it when the killer was driving him
他用指甲抓出来的
to that empty parking lot.
他刻在了金属里  所以没烧坏
He carved it into the metal. It survived the blaze.
他是想说明凶手的身份吗
Was he trying to I.D. his killer for us?
RTHDMN
"R-t h-d m-n"?
心腹
Right-hand man.
谁的心腹
Well, whose right-hand man?
洛克塞特的
LokSat's.
洛克塞特是谁
Who's LokSat?
卡莱布的消息是留给贝克特的
Caleb left that message for Beckett.
你还没回答问题  维克拉姆
You're still not answering the question, Vikram.
洛克塞特是谁
Who the hell is LokSat?
大恶狼
The Big Bad Wolf.
布莱肯参议员  艾莉森·海德  杀人小队
The person behind Senator Bracken, Allison Hyde,
和这九个月来发生在
the hit squads -- every terrible thing
我和贝克特身上的每件坏事的幕后黑手
that's happened to me and Beckett for the past nine months.
你不该告诉他们的
You shouldn't have told them.
是啊  该你来说的
Yeah. You should've.
全部告诉我们
Now tell us everything.
走吧
Come on.
不不不  他是好人  他是好人
No, no, no, no, no, no. He's okay, he's okay, he's okay.
你可算来了
It's about bloody time you got here.
理查德  亲爱的
Oh, Richard. Darling.
谢天谢地你没事
Oh, thank goodness you're all right.
谢谢
Thank you.
-凯瑟琳呢  -她就来
- Where's Katherine? - She's coming.
怎么回事
So, what's going on?
我们为什么被封锁了
W-Why are we on lockdown?
你没说吗
You didn't tell them?
考虑到危险程度  我觉得不该我来说
Considering the danger, I didn't think it was my place.
爸爸  这跟你在洛杉矶查明的事
Dad, does this have something to do with
有什么关系吗
what you found out in L.A.?
当然  很抱歉
Of course. I apologize.
你俩都有权知道
Uh, y-you both have a right to know.
这一切是...
This all started when...
那么卡莱布被活活烧死是因为洛克塞特
So, Caleb was burned alive because LokSat found out
发现他倒戈帮你们了
that he switched sides and was working with you?
现在洛克塞特会追杀维克拉姆  卡塞尔  我
Yeah, and now LokSat is going after Vikram, Castle, me --
所有知道他们的人
anyone that knows anything about them.
你们得忘记
So, I need you guys to forget
你们刚刚听到的一切
everything that you just heard.
不  我们做不到  老大
Oh, no, afraid we can't do that, boss.
洛克塞特干掉了我整支总检察长办公室的团队
You guys, LokSat took out my entire AG team.
我不要你们也出这种事
I'm not gonna let that happen to you.
我们不会让你不带
And we're not gonna let you go to war
最好的两个战士就上战场的
without your two best soldiers.
现在  根本没有仗可打
Right now there's no war to be fought.
卡塞尔和我可能
Castle and I are probably
得消失一阵
gonna have to disappear for awhile --
至少直到我们找到有关洛克塞特的新线索
at least until we find another lead on LokSat.
贝克特  我们已经有了
Beckett, we already have one.
卡莱布留下了凶手身份
Caleb I.D.'d his killer.
洛克塞特的心腹  知道这意味着什么吗
LokSat's right-hand man. You know what this means?
抓到杀卡莱布的凶手就能找到洛克塞特
Catching Caleb's killer will put us on a path to LokSat.
我找到他了
Guys, I got him.
-心腹  -是的
- The right-hand man? - Yeah.
我在卡莱布的信用卡记录上找到一处线索
I found a credit-card hit off of Caleb's financials.
他昨晚在一家餐馆单独进了餐
He ate alone at a diner last night.
他们刚把停车场的监控发给我
They just e-mailed me the security-cam footage from the parking lot.
那是卡莱布拿着个箱子吗
That's Caleb with the briefcase?
是的  那肯定就是洛克塞特的心腹了
Yes. And that's got to be LokSat's right-hand man.
这就发生在他烧死卡莱布之前
So, this is right before he torched Caleb.
他根本毫无胜算
He never had a chance.
能做面部识别吗
Can you run facial recognition?
不能  只能看到侧脸
No, we only have his profile.
洛克塞特和他的清道夫让我们抱头鼠窜
LokSat and his cleaner have had us running for cover
好像他们才是猎人
like they're the hunters.
那很好
That's good.
他们绝不会料到我们找上门
They'll never see us coming.
这可跟我们说好的不一样
That is not what we agreed to.
你该带上维克拉姆
You were supposed to grab Vikram
然后直接过来的
and then come straight here.
我知道  但是那是在他们
I-I know, but that was before the guys
都知情之前
were brought in on this
而且现在我们有了可用的针对洛克塞特的证据
and before we got actionable evidence on LokSat.
我现在不能走
I can't leave now.
那我要过去
Well, then I'm coming down there.
别  绝对不行
I -- No. No. Absolutely not.
你不能冒险暴露自己
You can't risk coming out in the open.
你不能冒险持续暴露呢
And you can't risk staying in the open.
卡塞尔
Castle,
警局是城里最安全的建筑之一
I am in one of the safest buildings in the city a police station
更好的是
a-and better yet,
这个警局是我的  里面都是我的警察
my police station with my cops.
我在这儿不会出事的
Nothing's gonna happen to me while I'm here.
贝克特警监
Captain Beckett.
亲爱的  我得挂了
Babe, I-I got to go.
你能留在警局吗
Will you stay at the precinct?
当然  我保证
Yes. I promise.
我就待在这里
I'll stay here.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
查到什么了
What do you got?
我们找到他了
We found him.
我们翻查了犯罪现场周围所有
So, we scrubbed through every available traffic cam
可用的监控  我们只找到一辆
around the crime scene, and we were only able to find
由于引擎中置而轮胎交错的车
one car with staggered wheels due to being mid-engine.
跟我们在犯罪现场
Which matches the tire impressions
发现的车辙也相符
we found at the crime scene.
这是离闲置停车场
This is the car five blocks
五个街区处的一辆车  正在驶离
from the vacant lot, driving away.
没有牌照  那我们如何知道
No plates. So, how do we know
是洛克塞特的心腹在开车
that LokSat's right-hand man is driving the car?
等等  利用监控
Just wait. Using traffic cams,
我们可以追踪车到我们假定应该是他家的地方
we can follow the car to what we assume is his house.
那就是他
That's him, all right.
房子是谁的
Who owns the home?
一家空壳公司
A shell corporation.
快看
Now watch.
这是实况监控  他还在里面
This is a live shot. He's still there.
好  拿好装备  我们去房子那
All right, grab your tac gear. We're going to that house.
等一下  贝克特
Excuse me, Beckett.
如果我说错就纠正我  你不是刚跟卡塞尔说
Correct me if I'm wrong, but didn't you just tell Castle
你要待在警局不轻举妄动吗
that you're staying put here at the precinct?
你觉得我会让你们去以身犯险
You think I'm gonna send you into harm's way
而自己却安然无恙地坐在这吗
while I'm sitting safe behind a desk?
不  肯定不行
No. Not gonna happen.
你已经被盯上了  而我们没有
You got a target on your back, we don't.
你就待在这
You're staying here.
他知道我才是警监对吧
Uh, he does know that I'm captain, right?
是的  长官
Yes, ma'am.
你要是想  也可以凭违抗命令解雇我们
You can fire us both for insubordination if you want.
不然的话  就让我们来处理
Otherwise, we got this.
烈性梅洛酒  优雅丰盛的酒宴
A feisty Merlot, an elegant spread,
还有这么棒的陪伴
delightful company --
要不是我害怕得要命
If I wasn't scared out of my mind,
这个下午还挺美好的
this would be a lovely afternoon.
我应该跟凯特在一起
I should be with Kate.
我向她保证过我们会一起扳倒洛克塞特
I promised her we'd take down LokSat together.
你也保证过你会待在这里
You also promised you'd stay here.
-我要去警局  -不要
- I'm going to the precinct. - Oh, no.
-我会没事的  别担心  -我觉得别
- I'll be fine. Don't worry. Don't worry. - I don't think --
没事的
Hey, it's okay.
It's fine.
我会没事的
I'll be fine.
别担心  我们很快就能见面
Don't worry. I will see you soon.
好吗
Okay?
待会见
See you soon.
你要干嘛
What are you doing?
你不能一个人出去
You can't go out there alone.
得有人看着你
Someone has to watch your back.
但也得有人照看好她们
And someone has to watch theirs.
我不了解门口这些人  我了解你
I don't know those guys out front. I know you.
跟她们待在一起  拜托了
Stay with them. Please.
不用  我有武器  我装备完善  我会没事的
No need. I'm armed. I'm packing. See? I'll be fine.
小心点
Be careful.
好了贝克特  我们准备冲进去了
All right, Beckett, we're ready to breach.
行动
Go.
纽约警局
NYPD!
前进
Move!
客厅安全
Front room clear!
房里安全
Room all clear!
查看衣柜
Get the closets.
安全
Clear!
拜托伙计们  说话  你们看到了什么
Come on, guys. Talk to me. What do you see?
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
卧室安全
Bedroom clear!
安全
Clear!
这地方是空的  警监
Place is empty, Captain.
空的的意思就是完全空的
By empty, we mean completely empty --
没有家具  没有那个心腹  什么都没有
No furniture, no right-hand man, no nothing.
贝克特  他把我们耍了
Beckett, he tricked us.
去12区分局第24跟7街区之间  快点
12th precinct, please -- 24th and 7th, fast as you can.
没问题  朋友
You got it, pal.
*我听到啦  不能整日待在家里*
*I hear ya now, I just can't stay inside all day*
*我得出去  晒晒太阳*
*I got to get out, get me some of those raaays*
这首歌多好听啊
Don't you just love this song?
*大家都在笑  晴朗的一天*
*Everybody's laughin', sunshine day*
鉴证组正在彻底搜查那地方
CSU is taking the place apart.
他们找不到什么线索的
They're not gonna find anything.
那地方只是个中转站
Place was a way station.
你觉得是他设计让我们跟着他去了那吗
You think he planned for us to follow him there?
洛克塞特的手下都是中情局的人
LokSat's people are CIA,
也就是说他们都很精通战术逃脱
which means they are experts at tactical subterfuge.
我猜那位"心腹先生"早就料到
My guess is "Mr. Right-Hand Man" anticipated
我们能在犯罪现场追踪到他的车
our ability to track down his vehicle from the crime scene,
他把我们引到了一个能摆脱我们的地方
and he led us to a place where he knew he could lose us.
你的猜想也许是对的
And your guess would be right.
房子后面那条街上的监控摄像
Surveillance cameras on the street behind the house
昨天早上发生了故障
were disabled yesterday morning.
所以我们要抓的这家伙从前门进
So, our guy walked right in the front door,
直接就从后门出去了
walked right out the back.
也就是说我们根本查不到他去了哪
Which means we have no way of knowing where he went.
很好
Good.
清醒且警惕
Awake and alert, I see.
你是谁
Who are you?
那重要吗
Does it matter?
我能理解  对一个作家来说
I understand that, as a writer, the naming of a thing
命名似乎有着非凡的意义
would seem to be of paramount importance,
但相信我  我的名字现在对你来说
but, trust me, my name is the least consequential thing
是最不重要的
for you to know right now.
你的名字一定很丢人  对不对
It's an embarrassing name, isn't it?
就像《一个叫苏的男孩》那样
Like "A Boy Named Sue"?
也许你妈妈叫你傻蛋
Maybe your mother called you doofus.
我的名字是国家起的
I was named by the state.
不过出任务的时候  我被称为弗林先生
But for operational purposes, I'm known as "Mr. Flynn,"
而这次我来负责对你的审问
and I've been entrusted with your interrogation.
等到一切结束的时候  你就会交代出
By the time we're done, you will have revealed the names
所有知道洛克赛特的人名
of everyone who knows about LokSat.
然后你就能杀了他们  别妄想了
So you can kill them? Forget it.
我不会告诉你任何事
I'm not telling you anything.
我不会背叛任何人
I'm not betraying anyone.
我才不在乎你要给我上多少拇指夹
I don't care how many thumbscrews you put to me.
不  我这人不待见严刑逼供
Oh, no. I don't believe in torture.
科学才更有效  并且局里
Science is much more effective, and the company
在化学吐真剂领域的研究颇有成果
has made great leaps in the field of chemical truth agents.
一个小时之内  你会告诉我
Within the hour, you will tell me
所有我想知道的事情
everything I want to know.
然后你就可以死了
And then you will die.
现在  老实告诉我
Now, tell me honestly,
知道我的名字还有那么重要吗
was knowing my name really that important?
这条线索不可能断掉
Dead end is not good enough.
那家伙不可能比我们更聪明
This guy doesn't get to be smarter than us.
现在有太多东西处于危险当中
There's too much at stake here.
如果失去这条线索  我们就只能坐以待毙
If we lose this thread, then we're just sitting ducks.
我需要一个奇迹  各位
I need a miracle, guys.
好吧  会有的
Okay. You got it.
奇迹马上就来
One miracle coming up.
卡塞尔
Castle?
不  我是梅森·伍德
No, it's Mason Wood.
我以为你已经和我们没关系了
Uh, I thought that you were done with us.
之前是  不过  不幸的是
I was, but, unfortunately for me,
也许我有条线索可以帮到你
I think I may have a lead that could help you.
什么样的线索
What kind of a lead?
早年我曾经共事的一个线人
A source that I worked with back in the early aughts,
他是个法外情报机构的服务人
he's a facilitator for extralegal intelligence operations.
如果说有谁了解中情局的阴暗面  一定是他
If anybody knows the dark side of the CIA, it's him.
很好  那我们去见他
Good. Then we'll go see him.
-不不  不是我们  是我  -不  梅森
- No, no, not we -- me. - No, uh, Mason --
那家伙默认这世界为
This guy's default setting
70年代早期的阴谋论惊悚小说
is early '70s conspiracy thriller.
他不会对你开口  见鬼  他可能都不会对我说
He won't talk to you. Hell, he might not even talk to me.
梅森  这是我的战斗
Mason, this is my fight,
你不知道应该问什么问题
and you're not gonna know the right questions to ask.
我必须去
I have to be there.
好吧  一小时后
All right, meet me in an hour
在格兰街和东百老汇的路口等我
at the corner of Grand and East Broadway.
剂量正确是关键
Correct dosage is the key --
必须恰好攻破中央皮层和大脑顶叶
just enough to compromise the central cortex and the parietal lobe.
过量就会...
Too much and --
这么说吧
let's just say that
忘记怎么呼吸可不是什么好玩的事情
forgetting how to breathe is kind of a drag.
我能问你个私人问题吗
Can I ask you a personal question?
不能
No.
就像我说的  我是由国家养大的
As I said, I was raised by the state.
我的成长过程中从来没有过一个家
I never had a family growing up.
我从来都不懂你所了解的那种爱
I never knew love in the way that you so clearly do.
不如你把我解开
Well, why don't you unstrap me?
我来给你一个大大的拥抱
I'll come give you a big hug.
我读过你的档案
I've read your files.
你在遇到凯瑟琳·贝克特之前
You were an incorrigible playboy
曾是个无可救药的花花公子
before you met Katherine Beckett.
是什么变了
What changed?
我爱上了她
I fell in love with her.
为什么
Why?
因为我从没有遇到过她那样的人
Because I'd never met anyone like her.
你也没见过我这样的人
Well, you've never met anyone like me.
是的  不过你没有她那样的大长腿  眼睛
Yeah, but you don't have the legs or the eyes...
智慧  和心灵
or the brains or the heart.
贝克特让我开怀大笑
Beckett makes me laugh.
她会质疑我
She challenges me.
我变成一个更好的人
I became a better man.
我为什么要对你说这些
W-Why am I telling you this?
对哦
Right.
但是这些感情让你变得脆弱
But these feelings make you vulnerable.
你肯定明白这一点
Surely, you must see that.
是啊  否则呢
Yeah, well, what's the alternative,
变得像你一样  独来独往毫无感情
to be like you, a man alone without empathy?
她是你躺在这里的罪魁祸首
She's the reason you are on this table.
如果你从未遇见她
If you never met her,
你还可以活很久
you'd most likely have a very long life ahead of you.
如果可以选择  你肯定会想重新来过
Surely, you would take a do-over if offered.
不  我不会的
No, I wouldn't.
有意思
Interesting.
她会找到你的  你还有洛克塞特
She's gonna find you -- you and LokSat.
而且她会把你们一网打尽
And she's gonna bury you both.
我现在不能说谎  对吧
And I can't tell a lie, right?
是的  但尽管你很相信这一点
Yes, but the fact that you believe it
也不能让它成为事实
does not make it the truth.
凯特·贝克特在今晚就会死去
Kate Beckett is going to be dead by the end of the night,
而且你对此也无能为力
and there is nothing you can do about it.
你看见贝克特了吗
You seen Beckett?
没有
No.
各位  我有发现
Hey, guys. I got something.
我从覆盖那座空房子的信号塔中
I pulled all active and passive cellphone signals
提取了所有来往的通话信号
originating from the cell tower that served the empty house.
肯定有几百通
Must have been hundreds.
是几千通
Try thousands.
有些让人望而却步
Which was daunting.
不过我又把它们跟心腹先生
But then I screened them against phone signals
从犯罪现场回到空房子的路线上的
along the route the Right-Hand Man took
信号在屏幕上做了交叉对比
from the crime scene to the house,
排除后  剩下的手机串号越来越少  直到...
and those IMEI numbers started to shrink until...
只剩一个
only one remained.
二位  那就是心腹先生的手机号
That, gentlemen, is Right-Hand Man's phone number.
你能确定他现在的位置吗
Can you locate where that phone is right now?
我可以试试
I could try.
谢谢分享你的个人体会
Thanks for sharing your personal feelings.
真的让我了解到很多事
They've given me some real insight.
其实  你不必这么做的
You know, you -- you don't have to do this.
很显然  你是想要更多的东西
Clearly, you're looking for something more.
不
Oh, no.
你误解我了
You misunderstood me.
我不是想要一个幸福的家庭
I'm not yearning for a happy family,
我只是想知道该如何分析它
simply insight into how best to dissect one.
现在  该做正事了
Now, time to get down to business.
听我说
Look...
能不能让我先去上个厕所
maybe I could make a quick trip to the little boys' room
然后你再问更多的问题
before we get started with any more questions?
最难的问题不是我来问
I won't be asking the hard questions.
谁来问
Who will?
我的老板  就是你们称为洛克塞特的人
My boss, the man you call LokSat.
意外吧
Surprise.
你就是洛克塞特
You are LokSat?
是的  不过准确来说  那只是一个代号
Yes, although, technically, that's the code name
用于我做的一些非法的事情
for my extralegal operations.
这么说  所有发生在洛杉矶的事
So, everything that happened in L.A.,
最强侦探协会  都是假的了
the GDS, that was all a lie?
不不不  最强侦探协会绝对是真的
Oh, no, no, no, no, the Greatest Detective Society is very real,
它跟我在中情局的事完全没关系
connected in no way to my work with the CIA.
算是我的一个  兴趣爱好吧
Think of it as a...fun hobby.
我的继母  她死了吗
My stepmother... is she dead?
还没有  不过你得相信我  这样我就能
Not yet, but I needed you to trust me so I could find out
在杀死你之前找出所有知道我的存在的人
who else knew about my existence before I kill you two.
我们赶紧开始吧  因为再过几分钟
So, let's get right to it because I have to meet your wife
我就要去见你妻子了  他准备好了吗
in just a few minutes. Is he ready?
-是的  长官  -好吧
- Yes, sir. - All right, then.
该说实话了
Truth time.
有谁知道我
Who knows about me?
很显然有贝克特  还有维克拉姆
Beckett, obviously, and Vikram.
那海莉·希普顿呢
What about Hayley Shipton?
知道
Yes.
莱恩和埃斯波西托警探呢
Detectives Ryan and Esposito?
知道
Yes.
你母亲呢
What about your mother?
知道
Yes.
你女儿呢
Your daughter?
-知道  -知道
- Yes. - Yes.
还有谁
Anyone else?
没有了
No.
很好
Good.
等这些人都死了
That will be a weight off my shoulders
我就彻底没有负担了
once everyone has been neutralized.
不要这么做  求你了
Don't do this, please.
失败没有什么可耻的  卡塞尔先生
There is no shame in losing, Mr. Castle...
你的傲慢让你觉得这事
only in the hubris that made you think
会是另一种结局  才是可耻的
that this could end any other way.
真是不忍心看啊
That was difficult to watch.
我相信你现在一定很自责
I'm sure you're finding it hard to live with yourself.
我理解
It's understandable...
知道自己所爱的人要遭受什么
knowing what's coming next for your loved ones.
这个  会让你不再痛了
This... will end your pain.
这个会结束一切
This will end everything.
纽约警局
NYPD.
我们有理由相信
We have reason to believe
这栋楼里有一个谋杀嫌疑犯
there's a murder suspect in this building,
我们得从头到尾搜查一边
and we need to search it from top to bottom.
抱歉  警官  但这不可能
Sorry, Officer, but that's not going to happen.
这栋楼属于美国中央情报局
This building belongs to the Central Intelligence Agency.
它受《国家安全法》保护
It's protected by the National Security Act.
我不能让你进去
I can't let you in.
就算它被绿巨人保护我也不在乎
I don't care if it's protected by the Hulk.
我们要把这个地方彻底查一遍
We're gonna tear this place apart.
这个人在哪
Where is this guy?
他在哪
Where is he?!
怎么  这次不用酒精帮我擦一下吗
What, no alcohol swab this time?
不需要  这东西能在12秒内杀死你
No need. This stuff will kill you in about 12 seconds.
或者  这次你听我的  我们可以跳过这步
Or -- and just roll with me on this -- we could skip it.
这件事没有必要非得是悲剧结局
There's no reason this has to end in tragedy.
所有事都是悲剧结局
Everything ends in tragedy,
包括你史诗一般的爱情故事
even an epic love story like yours.
纽约警局  举起手来
NYPD! Hands in the air now!
当然  我只需要把这个...
Of course. I just need to turn this --
莱恩
Ryan!
-你没事吧  -梅森·伍德就是洛克塞特
- You okay? - Mason Wood is LokSat.
他去对贝克特下手了
He's going after Beckett.
他会杀了她的  我们必须警告她
He's gonna kill her. We have to warn her.
调度  我是埃斯波西托  我需要支援
Dispatch, this is Esposito. I need backup.
这栋楼是一个秘密据点
This building is a black site.
所有的手机和无线电交流都被干扰了
All cell and radio communications are jammed.
我们得快走
We got to go.
我们走吧
Let's move!
走
Go.
叫他们停下来
Call them off!
就算我让他们停  他们也不会听我的
They wouldn't listen even if I asked them to --
何况我并不会那么做
which I won't.
梅森把贝克特带到哪去杀死
Where is Mason taking Beckett to kill her?
我不知道
I have no idea.
我们走着瞧
We'll see.
我希望我用的剂量是正确的
I sure hope I get the correct dosage
因为忘记呼吸  可不是什么好玩的事
because forgetting to breathe can be such a drag.
现在  你会告诉我我想知道的一切
Now you're gonna tell me everything I want to know.
梅森把贝克特带到哪去了
Where is Mason taking Beckett?
哪儿
Where?
就在这
Here.
这里的地下室有一间有焚化炉的杀人密室
There's a kill room in the basement with an incinerator.
本来你死后  我们就会把你丢进里面
That's where you were going to end up afterwards.
我怎么把这个消息传递给贝克特
How do I get a message to Beckett?
你做不到  我告诉过你了
You can't. I told you.
他们在警察到的那一刻
They shut down all the signals
关闭了所有的信号
the second the police arrived.
我们怎么出去
How do we get out of here?
你们出不去  那扇门是唯一的出口
You don't. That door is the only way out.
而他们的子弹比你们的多
And they have more bullets than you.
你和卡塞尔先生有着紧密的纽带
You and Mr. Castle have quite a bond --
这在你所处的行业中不多见
unusual in your line of work.
是啊  我为他疯狂  他是我一生的挚爱
Yeah, well, I'm crazy for him. He's the love of my life.
并且他理解
And he understands
我做这份工作所要做出的牺牲
the sacrifices that I have to make to do this job so...
显然  你所面对的对手非常危险
Clearly, whomever you're up against is quite deadly.
你有没有想过就此罢手
You ever consider just walking away?
每天都在想
Every day.
那为什么没有呢
Why didn't you?
我发过誓
I took an oath.
我所在乎的人被杀了
People that I cared about were murdered,
他们应当获得正义
and they deserve justice.
扛着这样的重担一定很辛苦
Must be hard carrying that weight.
我不是一个人扛着
I don't carry it alone.
我们到了
Here we are.
湿墙
The wet wall.
你在干什么
What are you doing?!
那是面向街道的一侧  你出不去
That's the street side! You can't get out!
我们不需要出去  我们可以进去
We don't have to get out! We can get in!
我们可以从这下面逃出去
We can escape down there!
如果我们不开枪  他们就要进来了
If we stop shooting, they're coming in!
别管我们了  去救贝克特
Don't worry about us! Go get Beckett!
所以  我们来这里见谁
So, who is this guy we're going to see?
他是  有点像是麦洛·明德宾德[小说人物]
Oh, he's...sort of a Milo Minderbinder.
我帮他找回了一些被偷的东西  所以他欠我人情
Owes me for retrieving some things that were stolen from him.
他会在这下面见我们
He's gonna meet us down here.
我告诉他你也会来
I told him you were coming.
你最好让我一个人跟他说话
You better let me do all the talking in the --
把枪从你的口袋里拿出来  用两个手指
Pull the gun out of your pocket -- two fingers.
把它放在地上
Put it on the ground.
别装了
Knock it off!
我知道是你
I know it's you.
现在  把枪放在地上  慢慢来
Now, gun on the floor -- nice and slow.
我就担心你太聪明了不会上当
I was, uh, worried you might be too smart to fall for this.
另一个口袋里有什么
What's in the other pocket?
这个吗  保险措施罢了
Oh, this? It's just insurance.
我的枪是塑料做的
See, mine is made of plastic,
不受天花板上的电磁铁影响
so it's unaffected by the electromagnet in the ceiling.
恐怕我还有其他坏消息
And I'm afraid I have some more bad news for you.
你丈夫死了
Your husband's dead.
你在骗我
You're lying.
不  没骗你
No, I'm not.
我去接你的时候他就死了
He died about the same time I was picking you up.
其实  他的尸体就在你身后的火炉里
As a matter of fact, his body is in the furnace behind you there,
已经烧成灰了
being reduced to a few pounds of ashes.
我觉得你们一起在烈火中永生
I think it's very fitting that your lives together
再合适不过了  你说呢
end in fire, don't you?
我不会不战而降的
I'm not going in there without a fight.
你很勇敢
That's very brave of you.
但是也不会有什么战斗了
But it won't be much of a fight.
把枪放下
Drop the gun!
否则我就杀了你
Or I will kill you.
卡塞尔  退后
Castle, stand back!
与此同时  戏剧化的一幕发生了
Meanwhile, in a dramatic scene,
数十名地方和联邦执法人员
dozens of local and federal law-enforcement officials
于今晚突袭了位于中城区的一栋大楼
descended on a building in Midtown tonight,
救出数名警察
rescuing several police officers
同时逮捕了十余人
and arresting almost a dozen people.
什么时候这件事和中情局的关系才能公之于众
How long before the CIA connection comes out?
用不了多久  这件事太大中情局也瞒不住了
Not long. It's too big a story for the agency to bury.
准备好出席大把听证会吧
Get ready for hearings out the wazoo.
-是啊  -终于结束了
- Yeah. - So, that's it.
我们终于了却了心头之患
We're finally in the clear.
所以我们要去酒吧庆祝一下  行吗
Yeah, so we're gonna go to a bar and celebrate, yeah?
去吧  玩得开心点
Okay, have fun.
这么说你要辞职了吗
So, you handing in your resignation?
不了
No.
无聊并没有那么好
Boring is overrated.
维克拉姆  一起来吗
Yo, Vikram, you coming?
现在是早上7点啊
It't 7:00 in the morning.
-纽约就这样啊  -是啊
- It's New York City. - Yeah.
我一会儿再吼你
I'm gonna yell at you later.
现在我替你们开心  都没事就好
But for now, I'm just glad you're both okay.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
蕾妮  一起来吗  来吧
Hey, Lanie. You coming? Come on.
-我们稍后再聊  -好
- Oh. I'll check you later. - Okay.
感觉我能睡上一周
Feel like I could sleep for a week.
先吃点早饭怎么样
How about some breakfast first?
这是开启冬眠模式的最好方式
Best way to start off a hibernation.
不如这样吧  我们叫外卖好了
Uh, you know what? Uh, why don't we just order in?
你不用下厨了
You don't have to cook.
我就爱为你下厨
I love cooking for you.
我就爱你为我下厨
And I love when you cook for me.
我去换衣服
I'm gonna go change.
好
All right.
贝克特
Beckett!
怎么了
Yeah?
如果梅森的地下室里有焚尸炉的话
If Mason had an incinerator in the basement,
他怎么不把卡莱布的尸体在那里处理掉
why wouldn't he just dispose of Caleb's body there?
我跟梅森说过你会发现这个问题的
I told Mason that you would figure it out.
卡塞尔
Castle?
但是那个老头子不听我的
But the old man wouldn't listen to me.
卡莱布  别
Caleb, don't...
对不起  里克  但是你和你太太
Sorry, Rick, but how am I gonna enjoy my retirement
对我穷追不舍的话  我怎么安心退休呢
with you and the missus hunting me?
卡塞尔
Castle!
到此为止吧
Well, guess this is it.
我们还可以继续啊
Doesn't have to be.
我们可以共进晚餐
We could, uh, go to dinner,
互相说下今天发生了什么事
debrief each other.
为什么  卡塞尔
Why, Castle?
好让我也成为你的"猎物"吗
So I can be another one of your conquests?
我做你的"猎物"也可以啊
Or I could be one of yours.
很高兴认识你  卡塞尔
It was nice to meet you, Castle.
太遗憾了  我们在一起会很幸福的
It's too bad. It would've been great.
你根本无法想象
You have no idea.
我找到了属于我的那一个
And I found mine.
直到永远
Always.